<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Gerald's Website</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Gerald's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://geraldwong.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I tried ChatGPT</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20230210_chatgpt_thoughts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20230210_chatgpt_thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been spending an unhealthy amount of time for the past 3 weeks playing around with ChatGPT instead of doing my work.
Seeing it evolve (some might argue &amp;lsquo;devolve&amp;rsquo;) day by day with &amp;lsquo;better&amp;rsquo; filters was interesting.
It&amp;rsquo;s quite amazing to see the different things it &lt;em>was&lt;/em> capable of.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cyberpunk 2077 thoughts</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20230114_cyberpunk_2077_thoughts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20230114_cyberpunk_2077_thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;p>I finally took the time to complete Cyberpunk 2077 today.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I played an open world western RPG.
I believe the last one I played was Skyrim when it first released in 2011.
&amp;hellip;man, that was really a long time ago.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Fallout 2</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20221217_fallout_2_thoughts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:44:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20221217_fallout_2_thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;p>I played Fallout 2 in 2022 and here are my thoughts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Fallout 1</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20221117_fallout_1_thoughts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 14:44:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20221117_fallout_1_thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;p>I played Fallout 1 in 2022 and here are my thoughts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on 'Stray'</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20220731_stray_thoughts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 13:40:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20220731_stray_thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;p>I just played this game called &amp;lsquo;Stray&amp;rsquo; over the week just to check out what all the hype was about.
Before I go on, I would like to say that it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty decent game.
I can see why there are people who loved and hate it.
Here I&amp;rsquo;m just going to pen down thoughts I find about the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sorry about the word vomit in advance, and of course, spoilers from here on!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Website Facelift</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20220724_website_facelift/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20220724_website_facelift/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s time for another facelift!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seriously though, I remembered liking the previous site design.
A year later, however, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t look at it straight in the eye anymore.
Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s because I developed a stronger opinion on what I want my site to be.
Here I&amp;rsquo;ll share some of my thoughts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deriving Triangle to Triangle transformation matrix</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20220425_derive_triangle_to_triangle_transform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 23:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20220425_derive_triangle_to_triangle_transform/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s how I derive the transformation matrix for getting from triangle A to triangle B to do shadows in my 2D engine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dots and Circles Afterthoughts</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20211201_dots_and_circles_afterthoughts-copy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 23:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20211201_dots_and_circles_afterthoughts-copy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Alright, the game is &lt;a href="https://momohoudai.itch.io/dots-and-circles">out on itch.io&lt;/a> for free! Now that some time has passed and a handful of people have played the game, I felt that there is no better time then to jot down my experiences developing this small arcade game, lest I forget (again).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Byte Alignment Notes</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20211118_bytes_alignment_notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20211118_bytes_alignment_notes/</guid><description>&lt;p>When dealing with raw memory directly, there might come the need to align your memory to the nearest of some power of 2.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dirty C/C++</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/dirty_c/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/dirty_c/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here is a collection of cool snippets of C/C++ code. Updated regularly. Used to show superiority and implode the minds of my students. Also to use in my own code, of course, whenever viable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perspective Projection Matrix</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20210801_perspective_projection_matrix/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20210801_perspective_projection_matrix/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was searching around internet for a full derivation for the 3D Perspective Projection Matrix to apply to my handmade software renderer and I was surprised by how little information I could find about it. That prompted me to write this post, to document the derivation of the matrix, at least in my own eyes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Circle to Finite Line Collision</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20210428_circle_line_collision/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20210428_circle_line_collision/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, I had to derive this particular collision detection algorithm for my bullet hell genre game. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting algorithm that can be expanded to deal with the &amp;lsquo;moving circle vs static circle&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;moving circle vs moving circle&amp;rsquo; problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>'Glue' C-preprocessor trick</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20210406_glue_c_preprocessor_trick/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20210406_glue_c_preprocessor_trick/</guid><description>&lt;p>Macro tricks are rare to find nowadays. Sometimes, I would code and &lt;em>know&lt;/em> of a trick but had forgotten how to go about implementing it because they can look as arcane as Template Metaprogramming. Hopefully, I can document some of my knowledge of these tricks in this blog. Here, I will introduce what I call the &amp;lsquo;Glue&amp;rsquo; macro trick.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A small shortcoming of return-by-value</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20210324_shortcomings_of_return_by_value_c_style_constructors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/blog/20210324_shortcomings_of_return_by_value_c_style_constructors/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, while coding on my personal C/C++ game engine project, I ran into a surprising shortcoming of functions that returns an object by value. This was when I was still trying to keep things consistant in my project and went for a functional-programming style.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AKB48の野望</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/industry/akb48/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/industry/akb48/</guid><description>AKB48&amp;rsquo;s Ambition (AKB48の野望) is a browser-based game by Koei Tecmo. It is based on a fantastical world where member of the popular idol group AKB48 battle out as witches.
The game was avaliable on several Japanese platforms such as Yahoo!mobage, myGameCity, dGame and GREE. As of 25th June 2018, the service for the game ended.
In this project, I worked in Japan for over a year as a full-stack developer.</description></item><item><title>Dots and Circles</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/projects/dnc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/projects/dnc/</guid><description>Be a Dot! Be a Circle! Be anything you want, just avoid what you are not!
Dots and Circles is an experimental Bullet Hell game that uses mouse as movement. Collect as many bullets as you can to see how much you can score!
Move around with the mouse Left click to change between being a Dot or a Circle. This game and its engine is written from scratch with the &amp;lsquo;handmade&amp;rsquo; philosophy.</description></item><item><title>Dots and Circles</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/student/dnc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/student/dnc/</guid><description>Dots n&amp;rsquo; Circles is a 2D Projectile Dodging/Collecting Game Hybrid. The player will control the character movement (Morphing One) with their mouse. The Morphing One has two forms - Dot forms and Circle forms, which players can switch using the left mouse button. Collect as many projectiles with the same form as the Morphing One! But beware, projectiles of the opposite form will harm you!
This game is a GAM100 student project written by a team of 2 for DigiPen Institute of Technology, Singapore.</description></item><item><title>Echolight</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/student/echolight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/student/echolight/</guid><description>Echolight is a real-time puzzle game! Create circuits using special bumpers to touch the stars, which will light up the dark and lonely world in this inventive puzzle game.
This game is a GAM200/250 student project written by a team of 4 for DigiPen Institute of Technology, Singapore. It is mostly coded from ground up in C/C++ for Windows. Only DirectX and FMOD libraries were used.
My responsibilities as a Tech Lead include:</description></item><item><title>Flocking</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/projects/flocking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/projects/flocking/</guid><description>This is a flocking demo written in the very fun to use p5.js over a weekend. It is only tested on Chrome, so some features might not be avaliable on other browsers.
git - play</description></item><item><title>Fun Links</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/fun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/fun/</guid><description>What is this This is personal list of links I use for inspiration and gamedev which I have personally evaluated and deemed useful or interesting. Thus, a lot of these drive how I work, program and think.
Streams/Videos for inspiration Handmade Hero: Stream that captures win32 low-level game engine development from scratch with minimal libraries used. Jonathan Blow: Stream of the creator of Braid, The Witness and the JAI programming language Chinnykian: Singaporean indie game developer momohoudai: My stream Computerphile: Generally good videos on anything computers Numberphile: Generally good videos on anything math Tools Compiler explorer: Useful to debunk any &amp;ldquo;this code runs faster&amp;rdquo; thoughts in your head.</description></item><item><title>Gods Only Love Me</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/student/gods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/student/gods/</guid><description>The Gods Love Me is a running game for the Android platform. Players have to interact with the environment and enemies to guide Kung Pao to safety on this simple 2D game!
This game is a GAM400 student project written by a team of 3 for DigiPen Institute of Technology, Singapore. It is coded in Java with LibGDX and Box2D for Android devices, in an attempt to explore the mobile market which was very new at the time this was created.</description></item><item><title>Gundam Heroes</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/industry/gundam-heroes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/industry/gundam-heroes/</guid><description>Gundam Heroes is a PC browser game published by Bandai Namco. It is a real time strategy game where players will command a team of heroes from the Gundam series to battle against other enemy teams.
The game was only avaliable in Japan and is currently not in service.
I was part of the team based in Koei Tecmo outsourced to implement a part of the game. Our responsibilities include implementing features outside of the main game such as matchmaking lobbies, guild systems and player information windows.</description></item><item><title>HIT</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/student/hit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/student/hit/</guid><description>Heavy Indestructable Tanks is a multiplayer party game inspired by. You are a Tank, and you are Indesctructable. However, your enemies are too! Fire at their feet and sink the ground under them till nothing is left beneath them; that will ensure their fate.
This game is a GAM150 student project written by a team of 4 for Digipen Institute of Technology, Singapore. The game is mostly coded from ground up using C/C++.</description></item><item><title>Karu's Dream</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/projects/karus-dream/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/projects/karus-dream/</guid><description>Karu&amp;rsquo;s Dream is a game prototype written in C++17 using SDL2 with the EnTT library. It is a game where you play as Karu, trapped in a nightmare, a nightmare where he can only move left and right, and jump; he cannot stop. Monsters will appear from the sides to eat him and touching them is fatal. Equipped with only a sword, try to defeat as many monsters as possible!</description></item><item><title>Mallory</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/projects/mallory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/projects/mallory/</guid><description>Mallory is a simple game prototype I made in Unity. It is an endless vertical jumping platformer, where players try to climb as high as they can and leave their mark!
The motivation is to explore procedurally generated levels and also using Unity as an engine.
I will probably create a more optimal desktop version some time in the future.
git - play</description></item><item><title>N-Puzzle</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/projects/npuzzle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/projects/npuzzle/</guid><description>This small project is simply an N-Puzzle demo and solver written in HTML5 using PhaserJS. The goal was to mostly to explore creating games in web-browser space, dealing with variable resolution changes and limitations with Javascript.
The amazing random artworks were created by @hikaika_guu.
Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll release a more optimized native version that can handle variable NxM puzzles one day&amp;hellip;
git - play</description></item><item><title>Nightmare</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/student/nightmare/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/student/nightmare/</guid><description>Nightmare is an Action Adventure game where the player have to save Tandy from her nightmare. Use your mouse to sprinkle fairy dust on the swarming monsters! Banish them from the dream world as Tandy tries to find a way out of this nightmare!
The game is a GAM300/350 student project written by a team of 7 for DigiPen Institute of Technology, Singapore. It is mostly coded from ground up in C/C++ for Windows, with only DirectX and FMOD libraries used.</description></item><item><title>Nobunaga's Ambition: Taishi</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/industry/taishi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/industry/taishi/</guid><description>Nobunaga&amp;rsquo;s Ambition: Taishi is a AAA title by Koei Tecmo. It is a historical simulation strategy game based on the Warring States of Japan. The game is avaliable on PC and PS4.
My team was involved in localizing the game into English. Our repsonsibilities include extension of tools and code to support the language, management of art assets and text translations, and various user-interface modifications.</description></item><item><title>Nobunyaga's Ambition</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/industry/nyaga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/industry/nyaga/</guid><description>Nobunyaga&amp;rsquo;s Ambition (のぶニャがの野望) is a browser-based game by Koei Tecmo. It is based on Japan&amp;rsquo;s Sengoku Period, with its characters anthropomorphized as cats.
The game is in Japanese and had been localized into Traditional Chinese, Simplified Chinese and English. In Japan, it&amp;rsquo;s avaliable on several platforms such as Yahoo!mobage, myGameCity, dGame, niconico, mixi and colopl.
Overseas, it&amp;rsquo;s avaliable on the platforms Wasabii (Taiwan) and Blue Panda (China). It also has webview applications on iOS and Android.</description></item><item><title>Paper Heroes</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/industry/paper-heroes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/industry/paper-heroes/</guid><description>Paper Heroes is a Android game written with Unity by UDream Entertainment. It is a lightweight, casual and idle strategy game, where you form your team of paper-styled pirates and battle against other crews
The game is currently avaliable globally on Play Store.
In this project, I worked as a backend engineer. My responsibilities include the backend architecture of the game, which includes server-side gameplay code, build/deployment pipeline, structuring databases and determining the data pipeline for business analytics.</description></item><item><title>Pathfinding Visualizer</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/projects/pathfinding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/projects/pathfinding/</guid><description>This is a pathfinding visualizer and maze generator I wrote for my lectures related to data structures. It is written in ReactJS.
Maze generation algorithms:
Recursive Division Pathfinding algorithms:
Depth First Search Breadth First Search Dijkstra A Star git - play</description></item><item><title>Portfolio</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/portfolio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/portfolio/</guid><description>I started in Koei Tecmo Singapore, where I worked as a full-stack web developer for the localization team in Nobunyaga&amp;rsquo;s Ambition.
I was then transfered to Japan to be a web developer for AKB48&amp;rsquo;s Ambition.
When I returned to Singapore, I primarily worked on localization of AAA console titles such as Nobunaga&amp;rsquo;s Ambition: Taishi and RTK13.
After 5 years in Koei Tecmo, I decided to try my hands in teaching in DigiPen Singapore.</description></item><item><title>Romance of the Three Kingdom 13</title><link>https://geraldwong.net/industry/rtk13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geraldwong.net/industry/rtk13/</guid><description>Romance of the Three Kingdoms 13 is a historical simulation strategy game based on the famous &amp;ldquo;Romance of the Three Kingdoms&amp;rdquo; novel. It is avaliable on PC, PS4, PS3, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch and PSVita.
My team was involved in localizing the Power Up Kit expansion into English and Korean, releasing it to Steam, PS3, PS4 and Xbox One. Our repsonsibilities include extension of tools and code to support the language,management of art assets and text translations, and user-interface modifications.</description></item></channel></rss>