<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Design on</title><link>/tags/design/</link><description>Recent content in Design on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 14:44:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Review: Little Nightmares</title><link>/blog/reviews/20240907_little_nightmares/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 14:44:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/reviews/20240907_little_nightmares/</guid><description>&lt;p>I realized that I haven't written about Little Nightmares after playing it on stream some time ago, so here we go. I think it slipped my mind because it's kind of difficult to describe a game like this to me. Perhaps it is because of the aesthetic direction the game took.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review: Ghost Trick</title><link>/blog/reviews/20240615_ghost_trick/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/reviews/20240615_ghost_trick/</guid><description>&lt;p>After many recommendations, I finally picked up and completed Ghost Trick. To be honest, I have nothing but praises for this game. 11/10 must play.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review: Citizen Sleeper</title><link>/blog/reviews/20240530_citizen_sleeper/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/reviews/20240530_citizen_sleeper/</guid><description>&lt;p>Citizen Sleeper was a very strange game to play to me and it was even stranger to think about how it came to be highly rated. I suspect that it shows that something surreal is happening to how people view games.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review: Viewfinder</title><link>/blog/reviews/20240407_viewfinder/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/reviews/20240407_viewfinder/</guid><description>&lt;p>I remember looking at the trailer for Viewfinder and was immediately intrigued. It's the kind of game where I'm not only interested in its mechanics' technology but also curious about the kind of levels they are going to make.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review: Potion Craft</title><link>/blog/reviews/20240123_potion_craft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/reviews/20240123_potion_craft/</guid><description>&lt;p>I first played this game during its early access when it was first released. There's a lot of the game that I liked and didn't like but I figured that I figured that I'll put my opinions on hold until its release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that it's released, I played it till the end and apparently my opinions about it didn't change much.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review: Persona 4 Golden</title><link>/blog/reviews/20231114_p4g/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/reviews/20231114_p4g/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post is just going to be some ramblings I have after completing Persona 4 Golden in 2023.
Let's get the easy stuff out of the way first. The game has amazing music, UI, art style and theme.
The team has always been excellent in these aspects and are often brought up in case studies in my classes.
With that out of the way, here are my thoughts on my playthrough.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Postmorterm: LIT</title><link>/blog/reviews/20230810_primix/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 23:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/reviews/20230810_primix/</guid><description>&lt;p>Alright, the game is &lt;a href="https://momolabo.itch.io/lit">out on itch.io&lt;/a> for free.
This is the 2nd game I have made using a rewrite of the engine I used in &lt;a href="https://momolabo.itch.io/dots_and_circles">dots and circles&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review: Return To Obra Dinn</title><link>/blog/reviews/20230402_return_to_obra_dinn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 12:31:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/reviews/20230402_return_to_obra_dinn/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had this game for awhile now in my Steam library, but like all games on it, I never took managed to allocate time for it until a friend speaks about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review: Cyberpunk 2077</title><link>/blog/reviews/20230114_cyberpunk_2077/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/reviews/20230114_cyberpunk_2077/</guid><description>&lt;p>I finally took the time to complete Cyberpunk 2077 today.
It's been a while since I played an open world western RPG.
I believe the last one I played was Skyrim when it first released in 2011.
...man, that was really a long time ago.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review: Fallout 2</title><link>/blog/reviews/20221217_fallout_2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:44:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/reviews/20221217_fallout_2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I played Fallout 2 in 2022 and here are my thoughts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like Fallout 1, I have also played Fallout 2 as a kid. Just like Fallout 1, it's so refreshing to play it in 2022.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review: Fallout 1</title><link>/blog/reviews/20221117_fallout_1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 14:44:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/reviews/20221117_fallout_1/</guid><description>&lt;p>I played Fallout 1 in 2022 and here are my thoughts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, let me give a disclaimer and say that I have played Fallout 1 as a kid when the game is still in a CD.
I remember positive emotions playing the game but all I remembered as an adult before playing it again was that you are the Vault Dweller from Vault 13 and you need to find a water chip within some kind of a time limit.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>