<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Student Projects on</title><link>/student/</link><description>Recent content in Student Projects on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/student/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dots and Circles</title><link>/student/dnc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/student/dnc/</guid><description>&lt;div class="showcase-img-wrapper">
 &lt;img class="showcase-img" src=/img/student/show-dnc.jpg />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dots n' Circles&lt;/strong> is a 2D Projectile Dodging/Collecting Game Hybrid. The player will control the character movement (Morphing One) with their mouse. The Morphing One has two forms - Dot forms and Circle forms, which players can switch using the left mouse button. Collect as many projectiles with the same form as the Morphing One! But beware, projectiles of the opposite form will harm you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This game is a GAM100 student project written by a team of 2 for DigiPen Institute of Technology, Singapore. It is coded using DigiPen's inhouse ProjectFUN engine for Window, with C/C++ as its main scripting language.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Echolight</title><link>/student/echolight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/student/echolight/</guid><description>&lt;div class="showcase-img-wrapper">
 &lt;img class="showcase-img" src=/img/student/show-echolight.jpg />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Echolight&lt;/strong> is a real-time puzzle game! Create circuits using special bumpers to touch the stars, which will light up the dark and lonely world in this inventive puzzle game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This game is a GAM200/250 student project written by a team of 4 for DigiPen Institute of Technology, Singapore. It is mostly coded from ground up in C/C++ for Windows. Only DirectX and FMOD libraries were used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My responsibilities as a Tech Lead include:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gods Only Love Me</title><link>/student/gods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/student/gods/</guid><description>&lt;div class="showcase-img-wrapper">
 &lt;img class="showcase-img" src=/img/student/show-gods.jpg />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Gods Love Me&lt;/strong> is a running game for the Android platform. Players have to interact with the environment and enemies to guide Kung Pao to safety on this simple 2D game!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This game is a GAM400 student project written by a team of 3 for DigiPen Institute of Technology, Singapore. It is coded in Java with LibGDX and Box2D for Android devices, in an attempt to explore the mobile market which was very new at the time this was created.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HIT</title><link>/student/hit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/student/hit/</guid><description>&lt;div class="showcase-img-wrapper">
 &lt;img class="showcase-img" src=/img/student/show-hit.jpg />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Heavy Indestructable Tanks&lt;/strong> is a multiplayer party game inspired by. You are a Tank, and you are Indesctructable. However, your enemies are too! Fire at their feet and sink the ground under them till nothing is left beneath them; that will ensure their fate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This game is a GAM150 student project written by a team of 4 for Digipen Institute of Technology, Singapore. The game is mostly coded from ground up using C/C++. Only the FMOD library is used.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nightmare</title><link>/student/nightmare/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/student/nightmare/</guid><description>&lt;div class="showcase-img-wrapper">
 &lt;img class="showcase-img" src=/img/student/show-nightmare.jpg />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Nightmare&lt;/strong> is an Action Adventure game where the player have to save Tandy from her nightmare. Use your mouse to sprinkle fairy dust on the swarming monsters! Banish them from the dream world as Tandy tries to find a way out of this nightmare!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The game is a GAM300/350 student project written by a team of 7 for DigiPen Institute of Technology, Singapore. It is mostly coded from ground up in C/C++ for Windows, with only DirectX and FMOD libraries used.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>