<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>yaps on</title><link>/blog/yaps/</link><description>Recent content in yaps on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/yaps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Future of games?</title><link>/blog/yaps/20250710_future_of_games/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20250710_future_of_games/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I stumbled upon a really insightful tweet chain talking about the connection between games and AI. I felt the need to react to each of the tweet because I have so much thoughts and feelings that I felt that I need to get off my chest.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Back from Japan</title><link>/blog/yaps/20250328_back_from_japan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20250328_back_from_japan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last month was going to be the last leg of me living in Japan. I thought it will be meaningful to write something about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reflecting on 2024</title><link>/blog/yaps/20250111_reflecting_2024/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20250111_reflecting_2024/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was considering posting this on social media or my own private journal but I decided to post this here which is... kind of public but not really. I thought some amount of publicity is good because it does make me think more about what I'm about to write (my private journal entries are not very introspective and tend to spiral badly, which is great for capturing raw emotions but not useful this time I reckon).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Guess who left their passport in laundry</title><link>/blog/yaps/20241030_idiot_for_damaging_passport/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20241030_idiot_for_damaging_passport/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Guess which idiot left their passport in the laundry.
Yes it is I.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>About doing a CS Masters</title><link>/blog/yaps/20241024_about_doing_masters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20241024_about_doing_masters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So some people close to me have been suggesting that I do a Masters in CS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about it on and off, and to be honest there's a part of me that feels pressured and stressed about it that made me want to start this post.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Programming journey reflection</title><link>/blog/yaps/20241022_programming_journey_reflection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20241022_programming_journey_reflection/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, this is just going to be a ranty reflection I wanted to do for some time now about my programming journey. I'm writing this now because I don't think that I will have any more drastic changes in my programming journey, well at least not in the next 20 years. Programming is also becoming less and less my livelihood as I attempt to spend more time exploring other crafts. Anyway!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Complaint about Complaints</title><link>/blog/yaps/20240825_complaint_about_complants/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20240825_complaint_about_complants/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I want to yap about working as a lecturer in a university that prepare students for the industry like a trade school. Specifically, I want to yap about specific members of a specific industry saying stuff about my school.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hokkaido</title><link>/blog/yaps/20240815_hokkaido_trip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20240815_hokkaido_trip/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hokkaido was...interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was interestingly &lt;em&gt;american&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thinking about changing the site</title><link>/blog/yaps/20240801_thinking_about_changing_the_site/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20240801_thinking_about_changing_the_site/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was looking at this very website recently and, for some strange reason, I felt a lot of feelings and thoughts about it. I don't exactly know what these feelings and thoughts are so many it's better to just articulate and put it out here as I try to process this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>100 questions revisited</title><link>/blog/yaps/20240602_100_questions_revisited/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20240602_100_questions_revisited/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was cleaning up my tumblr the other day (mostly because I discovered that tumblr can edit HTML so I went to theme it myself) and I came across a really old post of mine from 2016 answering like 100 questions. I thought it would be fun to do it again 8 years later and compare my old and new answers!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unity charging for runtime</title><link>/blog/yaps/20230920_thoughts_on_unity_charging_for_runtime/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20230920_thoughts_on_unity_charging_for_runtime/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, Unity announced about it's runtime charges, which will suddenly apply to all developers using the engine.
I feel I need to let out my raw thoughts about it because there is so many things to say and so many things to expect in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Japan is really something</title><link>/blog/yaps/20230502_japan_is_really_something/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 21:20:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20230502_japan_is_really_something/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I've lived in Japan for a year before for work purposes.
This time, I'm going to stay for a couple of years to accompany my wife as she does her Masters.
I thought that it would be fun to list down some random things that I personally find interesting about Japan, since this place is kind of like my 3rd home at this point.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I tried ChatGPT</title><link>/blog/yaps/20230210_chatgpt_thoughts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20230210_chatgpt_thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been spending an unhealthy amount of time for the past 3 weeks playing around with ChatGPT instead of doing my work.
Seeing it evolve (some might argue 'devolve') day by day with 'better' filters was interesting.
It's quite amazing to see the different things it &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; capable of.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Website Facelift</title><link>/blog/yaps/20220724_website_facelift/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/yaps/20220724_website_facelift/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It's time for another facelift!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously though, I remembered liking the previous site design.
A year later, however, I just couldn't look at it straight in the eye anymore.
Perhaps it's because I developed a stronger opinion on what I want my site to be.
Here I'll share some of my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>