<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Industries on</title><link>/industry/</link><description>Recent content in Industries on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/industry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AKB48の野望</title><link>/industry/akb48/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/industry/akb48/</guid><description>AKB48&amp;rsquo;s Ambition (AKB48の野望) is a browser-based game by Koei Tecmo. It is based on a fantastical world where member of the popular idol group AKB48 battle out as witches.
The game was avaliable on several Japanese platforms such as Yahoo!mobage, myGameCity, dGame and GREE. As of 25th June 2018, the service for the game ended.
In this project, I worked in Japan for over a year as a full-stack developer.</description></item><item><title>Gundam Heroes</title><link>/industry/gundam-heroes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/industry/gundam-heroes/</guid><description>Gundam Heroes is a PC browser game published by Bandai Namco. It is a real time strategy game where players will command a team of heroes from the Gundam series to battle against other enemy teams.
The game was only avaliable in Japan and is currently not in service.
I was part of the team based in Koei Tecmo outsourced to implement a part of the game. Our responsibilities include implementing features outside of the main game such as matchmaking lobbies, guild systems and player information windows.</description></item><item><title>Nobunaga's Ambition: Taishi</title><link>/industry/taishi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/industry/taishi/</guid><description>Nobunaga&amp;rsquo;s Ambition: Taishi is a AAA title by Koei Tecmo. It is a historical simulation strategy game based on the Warring States of Japan. The game is avaliable on PC and PS4.
My team was involved in localizing the game into English. Our repsonsibilities include extension of tools and code to support the language, management of art assets and text translations, and various user-interface modifications.</description></item><item><title>Nobunyaga's Ambition</title><link>/industry/nyaga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/industry/nyaga/</guid><description>Nobunyaga&amp;rsquo;s Ambition (のぶニャがの野望) is a browser-based game by Koei Tecmo. It is based on Japan&amp;rsquo;s Sengoku Period, with its characters anthropomorphized as cats.
The game is in Japanese and had been localized into Traditional Chinese, Simplified Chinese and English. In Japan, it&amp;rsquo;s avaliable on several platforms such as Yahoo!mobage, myGameCity, dGame, niconico, mixi and colopl.
Overseas, it&amp;rsquo;s avaliable on the platforms Wasabii (Taiwan) and Blue Panda (China). It also has webview applications on iOS and Android.</description></item><item><title>Paper Heroes</title><link>/industry/paper-heroes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/industry/paper-heroes/</guid><description>Paper Heroes is a Android game written with Unity by UDream Entertainment. It is a lightweight, casual and idle strategy game, where you form your team of paper-styled pirates and battle against other crews
The game is currently avaliable globally on Play Store.
In this project, I worked as a backend engineer. My responsibilities include the backend architecture of the game, which includes server-side gameplay code, build/deployment pipeline, structuring databases and determining the data pipeline for business analytics.</description></item><item><title>Romance of the Three Kingdom 13</title><link>/industry/rtk13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/industry/rtk13/</guid><description>Romance of the Three Kingdoms 13 is a historical simulation strategy game based on the famous &amp;ldquo;Romance of the Three Kingdoms&amp;rdquo; novel. It is avaliable on PC, PS4, PS3, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch and PSVita.
My team was involved in localizing the Power Up Kit expansion into English and Korean, releasing it to Steam, PS3, PS4 and Xbox One. Our repsonsibilities include extension of tools and code to support the language,management of art assets and text translations, and user-interface modifications.</description></item></channel></rss>